(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)ムガロを殺したのは誰だ!?
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)それ以上の侮辱は➡
Who killed Mugaro?
I will not tolerate any more insults!
許さぬぞ！
(ﾌｧﾊﾞﾛ･ﾚｵｰﾈ)あのｶﾞｷを殺したのは➡
The one who killed the kid
was Alessand.
アレサンドだ｡
(ﾃﾞｨｱｽ)また➡
This may mean another battle.
戦いになるかもしれませんな｡
(ﾆｰﾅ･ﾄﾞﾗﾝｺﾞ)これ以上 あの人が➡
If he's going to keep taking the
lives of the people I care about,
私の大切な人たちの命を
奪うなら➡
私が絶対に止める｡
then I will stop him.
(ｱｻﾞｾﾞﾙ)
今こそ アナティ進軍のときです｡
The time has come to march on Anatae.
Charioce XVII's reckless acts of violence
cannot be forgiven.
(ｼﾞｬﾝﾇ)
私は シャリオス１７世の暴挙を➡
決して許さない｡➡
Those who have suffered by his hands,
虐げられし者たちよ
２つの月が重なるとき➡
when the two moons align,
武器を取り
イーディスの丘へと集え｡➡
take up arms and assemble at Edith's hill.
Now is the hour for rebellion!
今こそ 反逆のときだ｡
Eibos!
(ﾊﾝｻ)エイボス…
１０年前の あの日以来ですねぇ｡
We haven't been there since that day ten years ago.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)王の野郎
あんな所で 何するつもりだ｡
What is that guy planning on doing there?
I've heard nothing can grow there
since the incident.
(ﾊﾝｻ)あの件で 草一つ生えない
焦土となったそうですクワァらね｡
Bacchus, we need to go faster.
バッカス もっと速く｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)バカ言うな｡➡
Don't be an idiot. If we go any faster, it'll kill Hippogriff.
これ以上 出したら
ヒッポグリフが死んじまう｡
(ｼｬﾌﾞﾛﾙ)いや～
バチバチきとりますなぁ｡➡
It's really sizzling.
封印と はざまが拡大する力｡➡
The power to expand the rift and seal it.
If their outputs continue to increase
このまま
互いの出力が高まり続ければ➡
we will reach the critical limit
at any moment.
間もなく 臨界点を超えますぞ｡➡
さすれば 大陸の半分が
消し飛ぶかもしれませんなぁ｡
When that happens,
half the continent might get blown away.
I know. We will release the seal
and continue with our plan.
(ｼｬﾘｵｽ17世)分かっている｡
封印を解除し 計画を進める｡
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー…
Rage of Bahamut
They are the same
And lose themselves
Cuz there are lots of roads to go
And the path suddenly seems rougher
I wanna walk straight ahead
Knock down another dream
Most broke before they ever came true
(連合軍)ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
But walk this way
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
Get out of my way
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
Depends on the way you think it
To a yielding heart
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
The future, hope,
Despair and worry all look all the same
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
So much that you'll turn down the truth
That lied to you that day
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
When you were prepared for it all
You go your way, don't you?
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
But walk this way
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！
ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！ ジｬンヌ！➡
Get out of my way
ジャンヌ！
But walk this way
よくぞ集ってくれた｡➡
I thank you for gathering today.
ここにいるのは皆
王と それに従う者たちにより➡
All of you here have suffered
憂き目に
遭ってきた者たちであろう｡
under the king and his men.
私は 息子を奪われた｡
My son was taken from me.
Victory will be ours!
この戦い 必ず勝つ！
ヒヒィーン！
進軍せよ！
Forward march!
(兵士)もたもたせず 早く行け！
Hurry it up, people!
また避難かい！ いいかげん
バカらしくなってきたよ｡
We have to evacuate again?
This is getting ridiculous.
じゃあ 戦のない国に引っ越すか!?
どこだ そりゃ！
Then you want to move to a country where
there's no war? Now where would that be?
ニーナがいた頃とは
随分変わっちまったな…｡
So much has changed
since when Nina was around.
(漆黒兵)一般兵は裏を固めろ｡
Have the regular troops secure the rear.
(隊長)
牢獄島の警備を最優先にしろ｡➡
Have them prioritize guarding the prison island.
他は捨ててもかまわん｡
They can ignore everything else.
We have to make sure nobody gets near Dromos.
ドロモスにだけは
何人たりとも近づけるな｡
Yes, sir.
We're up against humans.
人が相手か…｡
ごほっ ごほっ！
I heard most in the 2nd Battalion
joined the saint.
(兵士)第二の連中も
ほとんど 聖女に下ったんだとよ｡
(兵士)本当かよ？ 俺らも
便乗した方がよかったんじゃ…｡
Are you serious?
Maybe we should've jumped ship too.
(兵士)城の守りも薄いし
大丈夫かよ？ この戦い｡
Castle security is spread thin.
I'm not so sure about this battle.
(兵士)しかも よりによって
臨時の指揮官が あいつじゃな…｡
Not to mention we've got him in charge.
(兵士)おい 聞こえるぞ｡
Hey, quiet. He'll hear you.
(ｱﾚｻﾝﾄﾞ･心の声)≪ディアスさん
どこ行っちまったんだよ≫
Dias.
Where did you go?
違う…｡
No.
俺は悪くない｡➡
I didn't do anything wrong.
Jeanne, please listen to what I have to say.
ジャンヌ様
私の話を聞いてください｡
His Majesty was not involved
in your son's death. That was...
あなたのご子息の件に
王の意思はありません｡
あれは…｡
私の部下
アレサンドの単独行為です｡
My subordinate, Alessand, acting alone.
全ては ヤツを
アジトに引き入れた私の責任｡
It is all my responsibility,
as I am the one who invited him to our base.
(ｶｲｻﾞﾙ)このまま戦っても
無駄に血が流れるだけです｡
Fighting here would only needlessly spill blood.
どうか 進軍をおやめください｡
Please, halt this march.
(連合軍)おお～～！
なぜ？
Why?
エルを失ったことは
紛れもない事実｡
The truth of the matter is that I have lost El.
そして 王が エルの命を
狙い続けてきたことも また事実｡
And it is also true that the king
had continued to target El's life.
私は
エルに向けられた悪意を許さない｡
He is going to pay for the evils
that had been directed at El.
(軍神)どけ｡
Move.
They're here!
(兵士)来たぞ～！
≫カン カン カン カン！(警鐘)
神のご加護は我にあり！
God is my protector!
ドカーン！
いざ出陣！
(連合軍)おお～～！
All forces, charge!
(連合軍兵)
おらっ 行け 行け 行け～！
Go, go, go!
Rage of Bahamut
(ﾊﾝｻ)霧ばっかりで
何も見えませんねぇ｡
We can't see anything through this fog.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)なんだか きな臭ぇ霧だな｡
This fog sure seems fishy.
あっ？ なんだ？ ありゃ｡
What's that?
Bacchus, get closer.
バッカス 近づいて｡
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)大丈夫か？
-Are you sure?
-Just do it!
いいから！
(ﾊﾝｻ)クワァ～！
まずい！
This is bad!
(ﾊﾝｻ)あれは何なんでしょう？
What could that be?
This fog is probably camouflage.
この霧は
カモフラージュだなぁ たぶん｡
Seems like there's something down there
that they don't want us to see.
よほど見られちゃまずいものが
あの下にあるみてぇだな｡
いる｡
He's there.
(ﾊﾞｯｶｽ)まさか 王の野郎…｡
-You don't think the king--?
-Yeah.
ああ｡ まっ ちょっと 見てくる｡
-Well, time to go take a look.
-Wait, young lady!
≫(ﾊﾝｻ)あっ お嬢さん！
おっ｡
ったく…｡ んじゃ 行ってくる｡
We'll be back.
頼んだぞ ボンバーヘッド｡
We're counting on you, Bomber Head.
陛下？
Your Majesty.
≪(兵士)侵入者です！
Intruders!
バキッ バキッ！
バン バン！
おい
ちょっと 強引すぎやしねぇか？
Hey, don't you think you're being
a bit aggressive here? Come on!
もう～｡
ニーナ！
バキッ！
Nina!
はぁ～｡ 予想外の展開ですなぁ｡
This is an unexpected development.
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
やっぱ バハムートか｡
So it was Bahamut after all.
バハムート？
Bahamut?
Just what are you guys up to?
おめぇら 何たくらんでやがる？
It doesn't matter what you're up to.
何をたくらんでようが
かまわない｡
If you're going to take more lives
これ以上 命を奪うなら➡
私が止める！
then I'll stop you!
ガシャン！
おい！
Hey!
どうした？ やれ｡
What's the matter?
Do it!
ガキン！
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
(ｼｬﾌﾞﾛﾙ)
盛り上がってるところ悪いが➡
Sorry to interrupt,
そろそろ 脱出したいんだがのう｡
but I'd like to escape right about now.
正直に答えてくれよ｡ あんた
あの化け物 よみがえらせて➡
Answer me honestly.
What are you planning to do
after resurrecting that monster?
何する気だ？
Kid, you know nothing.
小僧 お前は 何も分かっとらん｡
あっ？ 邪魔すんな じじい｡
バハムートなぞ よみがえらせて➡
What? Don't interrupt us, old man.
Who would actually want to resurrect Bahamut?
誰が楽しいものか｡ そのお方が
やろうとしていることは➡
What he's trying to do is the opposite of that.
その逆だ！
これ以上 邪魔される方が
一大事なんでね｡
Interfering with us any further
would be detrimental.
話が見えねぇなぁ｡
王様を殺されたくなけりゃ➡
I'm having trouble seeing the big picture.
If you don't want me to kill the king,
then start explaining, old man.
教えてくれよ じじい｡
陛下の目的は➡
His Majesty wishes to slay Bahamut.
バハムート討伐にある｡
討伐って…｡
Slay?
まさか あの大砲でか？
Wait, with that cannon?
時間がないから
手短に教えてやる｡
I'll keep it brief, since we don't have time.
Ten years ago, there was a steward
who served the royal family,
１０年前 当時 王家に仕える
執事の一人であった男が➡
復興最中の城内で
ある隠し部屋を発見した｡➡
and he discovered a hidden room
while the castle was being renovated.
後に漆黒兵の隊長を担う男が
発見したその部屋は➡
This man would later become the leader
of the Onyx Soldiers.
史実からは隠された
バハムート事件の犯人の一人➡
The room he discovered
belonged to the demon Martinet,
マルチネと呼ばれた悪魔の
隠し部屋だった｡➡
who was one of the members
behind the Bahamut incident.
その古書には 一体どうやって
調べたのかは 分からんが➡
While I do not know exactly how
the information was uncovered,
バハムートによる破壊を
くわだてた際の情報と➡
this ancient text had facts regarding
the destruction caused by Bahamut
神々が封印する
古代の技術について➡
and meticulous details
regarding an ancient technology
事細かに 膨大に記されていた｡
that the gods had sealed away.
Martinet.
マルチネ…｡
(ｼｬﾌﾞﾛﾙ)そして わしらは➡
And as we studied the integrity of the text,
古書の内容の整合性を
図っていくうちに➡
滅ぼしきれなかった この大地に➡
we confirmed that Bahamut
必ず また
バハムートが現れることを➡
would inevitably return to these lands.
確信したのだ｡➡
その危機を回避するため 我々は➡
In order to avoid this danger,
we needed a king who possessed
incredible mental fortitude,
強靱な精神力を持つ
王を必要とし➡
共に バハムート討伐の計画を
進めたのだ｡
and together we went forward
with our plans to slay Bahamut.
なるほど｡
とても信じられねぇが…｡
I see.
Although it's hard to believe,
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
この雄たけびが 何よりの証拠だ｡
these roars should be all the proof you need.
で その手はどうした？
So what happened to your hand there?
黒い鎧のおっさんにも
同じようなあざがあった｡
The guy in the black armor had the same mark.
目ざといヤツめ｡
You've got sharp eyes.
何事も
なすためには代償が必要だ｡
Results require a cost.
We are laying Bahamut to rest.
バハムートを葬るのだ｡ 当然だろ｡
What did you expect?
それは同感だが
あんた 死ぬ気か？
I agree with what you're saying,
but are you looking to die?
その見えてない左目も
その計画の代償だろ？
Your blind left eye was part of the cost
for your plan too, right?
クリス！
Chris!
This is my destiny.
これは宿命だ｡ 母を
バハムートにより失ったときから➡
Ever since I lost my mother to Bahamut,
この運命は
私だけに定められたものだ｡
this fate was bestowed upon me.
だから…➡
So...
邪魔をしないでくれ｡
don't get in my way.
最後に聞かせてくれねぇか 王様｡
Let me ask you one last thing, king!
俺らが ここに来たとき
なんで ニーナを見て驚いた？
When we got here,
why did you look surprised to see Nina?
あの黒い鎧のおっさんに
ﾆｰﾅは死んだとでも言われたか？
Did that guy in the black armor
tell you that Nina died or something?
あのおっさんは あんたが
ニーナを始末するように➡
That guy said you ordered him
to take care of Nina, but that was a lie.
命令したと言ったが
そいつは うそだ｡
そんな命令すんなら 舞踏会の夜に
見逃す必要なんてないからな｡
That's because if you're going to give an order like that,
you wouldn't have let her go at the ball.
それに
ジャンヌのガキが殺されたのも➡
And you didn't order Jeanne's kid to be killed either.
あんたの命令じゃない｡
If your goal is to slay Bahamut,
あんたの目的が
バハムート討伐なら➡
then picking a fight with the gods now
would be the last thing you'd want.
このﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞで神にケンカを売るのは
百害あって一利なしだ｡
どうだ？
How am I doing?
ドドォーン！
今なら まだ間に合う｡
死にたくなければ去れ｡
There's still time.
Leave if you don't want to die.
あっ？ ちょっ… 待て！
What? Wait! Hold on!
それじゃあな 小僧｡
Well, see you, kid.
(ﾊﾞﾊﾑｰﾄ)グオォーー！
師匠！
これ なんとかなんないの!?
Master! Can't we do something about this?
お前… ええっ!?
ビリビリッ… ビリビリビリッ！
What? Are you crazy?
うわっ！
ドドォーン！
うわわっ…｡
おいおい やべぇぞ こりゃ｡
Hey, this is not good.
クワッ クワッ！ 来ました！
They're coming!
早く来い！
Hurry up!
跳べ ニーナ！
Jump, Nina!
Bacchus, we need to get farther away!
バッカス もっと離れろ！
分かってるっつぅの！ んっ｡
I know that already!
It's coming!
Get in formation.
We're taking him to Anatae.
It's been ten years.
As horrible as you are
I can't help but love you
Even while I waited
That is all I felt
Ephemeral lovers, both flawed and missing pieces
We have finally become one
in this miniature garden at the edge of sorrow
Can you hear my heart speaking?
Ah, I may no longer feel
That I want to go back in time
But there are feelings, feelings, feelings
I can only feel now
I want to run away with you, dancing
Just like in a fairy tale
Don't tell me it will only be this once, darling
I am on the same ark
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
来るぞ！
ドシュー！
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Cinderella step
ドカーン！
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Yeah
ドシュー ドシュー ドシュー！
Sha-ra-ran-la, Sha-ra-ran-la
Cinderella step
ドカーン！
Yeah
What's the matter?
ドカーン！
Master, I don't know what to do.
When you feel that way...
Here we go!
陣を組め！ ヤツを
このまま アナティへ連れていく！
Next time on Rage of Bahamut:
Virgin Soul, "Rise of the Nightmare."
-Which way is the wind blowing?
-Tomorrow!
Baha Baha Baha Soul!
Please watch next time too.
１０年ぶりだな｡
グオォーーー‼